TIM WEYEL

805-570-9159 | twevel@gmail.com | Goleta, CA 93117

LinkedIn: <u>/timweyel/</u> | GitHub: <u>/timweyel</u> | Portfolio: <u>timweyel.github.com</u>

Full Stack Software Engineer with a background in Product Management and Web Development looking for an entry/junior level position. Fully versed in end to end Agile Methodologies and the development process. Dedicated and loyal team member looking for a fun, hard working group to contribute to.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: MongoDB, GitHub, MySQL

Tools: React, Node, Express, Handlebars, Sequelize, ¡Query, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

masterTicket2.0 | github.com/masterTicket2.0 | masterticket2.herokuapp.com/

Refactored original masterTicket to use MERN stack

- Collaborated with 4 other team members using Agile methodologies to wireframe, design, develop, debug and deploy to production an app that met project requirements. React on front end, GraphQL with a Node.js and Express.js server. MongoDB and Mongoose ODM. Queries and mutations allowing for CRUD interactions. JWT authentication. Deployed with Heroku.
- Role: Frontend and backend developer. Specifically, I did the bulk of the work on the MyPosts, PostForm, PostList, and Featured components and much of the Dashboard page.
- Tools: React, JavaScript, GraphQL, Express, Apollo-Server-Express, Mongoose & MongoDB, Client-side debugging with Chrome DevTools.

Wine-and-Dine | github/wine-and-dine | github.io/wine-and-dine/

Users can select a type of wine they have and will receive a recipe for a meal that pairs well with the wine

- Project with a group of 5 where we worked together to create a web application that used a CSS
 framework other than Bootstrap, accepted and responded to user input, used at least two server-side
 APIs, and used client-side storage to store persistent data. Additionally, it needed to be responsive and
 deployed using GitHub pages.
- Role: Frontend and backend developer. Specifically, I worked on the saveWineHistory, getWineImage, infoCardGenerator, and getWineData functions in script.js and worked on the index.html page
- Tools: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, APIs from Spoonacular, Unsplash, and Cocktail DB, Client-side debugging with Chrome DevTools.

masterTicket | github/masterTicket | masterticket.herokuapp.com/

Blog-like site where users can post events and mark if they are attending

- Group project on a team of 5 in which we were tasked with creating a web application from scratch that
 used Node.js and Express.js to create a RESTful API, used Handlebars.js as the templating engine, and
 used MySQL and Sequelize ORM for the database. We needed GET and POST routes for retrieving and
 adding new data, have a folder structure that met the MVC paradigm, include authentication, and be
 deployed using Heroku. Additionally, the app needed to be responsive.
- Role: Frontend and backend developer. Specifically, I worked on the data models, post-routes.js, and dashboard.handlebars.js.

 Tools: React, Express, Handlebars, CSS, Bootstrap, Sequelize, MySQL, Client-side debugging with Chrome DevTools.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer

July 2021 - Present

Goleta, CA

I am currently working on various personal projects to continue to improve my development skills. I am currently working on a music player web app using React and GraphQL. For more details, please visit my GitHub account: https://github.com/timweyel.

Product Manager

May 2019 - September 2020

Scalable Commerce - Goleta, CA

Oversaw development of 5 different subscription-based websites to improve retention rates.

- Improved customer engagement by 12% by updating reporting design to improve usability and discoverability.
- Implemented a new reverse phone lookup feature that helped drive new revenue by 3%.
- Managed product roadmap and gating of projects from discovery to release.
- Worked directly with the development team to manage implementation of new features.

Director of Product August 2018 - April 2019

Orthobullets - Santa Barbara, CA

Recruited to lead 4 direct reports in the day-to-day management of firm's Study Plan product, the #1 online Orthopedic educational platform. Additionally oversaw development of Prime Meetings product, including integration of doctor profiles.

- Generated \$250K in first-year revenue for Prime Meeting by designing a mobile app in response to client requests.
- Collaborated with meeting health care administrators to ensure optimal performance of the company's Audience Response System during meetings.

Product Manager

August 2015 - February 2017

Procore Technologies - Santa Barbara, CA

Managed product backlogs for 3 development teams comprising 12 people using Scrum and Agile development methods. Led department-wide strategy synchronization meetings designed to leverage knowledge sharing and cross-functional collaboration.

- Reduced number of steps needed to upload photos in the Documents module 40%, greatly improving user experience, by implementing a major UI and UX upgrade in partnership with the team's UX designer.
- Significantly increased client dependency on Procore products and improved client satisfaction by creating a cloud sync utility that clients began implementing immediately after release.

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack JavaScript Web Development - UC Berkeley

Berkeley, CA

A 24-week intensive program allowing students to acquire technical skills in programming with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node, MySQL, Express, Sequelize, React, NoSQL, MongoDB, Handlebars